Finding Aid for the collection of Avon Books LSC.0427
UCLA Library Special Collections
Collection of Avon Books
1930-1969
1960-1969
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0427
26.0 Linear Feet (52 boxes and 1 oversize box)
Collection consists of an archive set up by the UCLA Library of all the books published by the Avon Book Division of the Hearst Corporation, beginning with March 1960.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Hearst Corporation.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942327053606533
Biography
The Avon Books Collection (Coll. 427) was begun by Special Collections in earnest in 1960, after the Hearst Corporation took over the Avon imprint. Collecting continued at least through 1969, with help, at least in part, from the publishers themselves. The collection also includes a number of Avon Books acquired from other sources prior to 1960, some as early as the 1930s. The alpha-numeric list below represents Avon's attempts to make discrete "series" through means of an alpha-numeric code, even though the nature of the coding is not always clear (in the early days, it was thought that the "G" stood for "giant"; indeed, the books with this alpha-prefix are indeed somewhat more serious than the general Avon content). All of the books have now been individually cataloged on Voyager, on Bib ID 4232705.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of an archive set up by the UCLA Library of all the books published by the Avon Books Division of the Hearst Corporation, beginning with Mar. 1960. Also includes a number of Avon Books acquired from other sources prior to that date, some as early as the 1930s. Titles include John Haase's The young who sin, Robert Payne's The blue Negro, Henry Miller's The air-conditioned nightmare, and Kenneth Rexroth's Classics revisited.
Organization and Arrangement
Collection is arranged by the publisher's alpha-numeric series designations.
Organization - mostly in alpha-numeric order per the series designation on spine.
Avon Books.
- Pre-Hearst Corp. items (Box 1)
- Pre-Hearst Corp. items; T397-412 (Box 2)
- T415-458 (Box 3)
- T459-506 (Box 4)
- T507-556 (Box 5)
- F100-150 (Box 6)
- F151-186 (Box 7)
- F187-245 (Box 8)
- D5-7; G0151-1057 (Box 9)
- G1058-1087 (Box 10)
- G1088-1119 (Box 11)
- G1120-1154 (Box 12)
- G1155-1190 (Box 13)
- G1191-1230 (Box 14)
- G1231-1261 (Box 15)
- G1262-1295 (Box 16)
- G1296-1343 (Box 17)
- H100-108; N101-114 (Box 18)
- N115-130 (Box 19)
- N131-147 (Box 20)
- N148-168 (Box 21)
- N169-189 (Box 22)
- N190-208 (Box 23)
- N209-230 (Box 24)
- Bard series: (in numerical order:) T07, T09, G10, 11, T12, G13; S101-120 (Box 25)
- S122-151 (Box 26)
- S152-189 (Box 27)
- S192-219 (Box 28)
- S220-257 (Box 29)
- S259-296 (Box 30)
- S297-336 (Box 31)
- S337-378 (Box 32)
- S379-400; V2032-2039 (Box 33)
- V2040-2056 (Box 34)
- V2057-2075 (Box 35)
- V2076-2097 (Box 36)
- V2098-2118 (Box 37)
- V2119-2141 (Box 38)
- V2142-2165 (Box 39)
- V2166-2191 (Box 40)
- V2193-2221 (Box 41)
- V2222-2252 (Box 42)
- V2254-2279 (Box 43)
- V2280-2301; W100-102 (Box 44)
- W103-122 (Box 45)
- W123-140 (Box 46)
- W141-156 (Box 47)
- Poster (36 × 24") advertising a book by Patrick Dennis (Box 48)
- W157-163; CS2; GS1-7, 11, 13, 16; NS1-14 (Box 49)
- NS15-22, 25-27, 29, 35, 39, 42-43; QS1-2, 4, 7, 9; SS3-10 (Box 50)
- SS11-12, 14-17; VS1, 4-7, 13, 16-18, 21 (Box 51)
- VS22-23, 27, 29; YN235-236; YQ10; ZN143, 149; ZS101, 105-107, 111-117, 119-120 (Box 52)
- ZS121, 124, 127-128, 131, 133-136, 139, 141, 146, 148, 150-151, 156, 158, 161, 163; ZV125, 140, 145, 153-155, 157, 164 (Box 53)